NICHOLAS ADAMOU

+1 203-788-6903 | nicholasadamouemail@gmail.com https://nicholasadamou.com

PROFILE

Performance-driven full-stack software engineer with a demonstrated history of working on the front-end and back-end of cloud-native applications Experienced in a wide range of web-based technologies. Highly skilled in software design, system architecture, software development, requirements analysis, and problem-solving. Graduated *Summa Cum Laude* in Computer Science at *Cornell College*. Currently pursuing a Master of Science in Computer Science at *Georgia Institute of Technology*.

EXPERIENCE

IBM

IBM

Staff Software Engineer

May 2021 – Present

Southbury, CT

- Lifted and shifted IBM's departmental application's chatbot to the ledger application.
- Utilized Box SDK and Java Spring Boot to send video embeds and images to the chatbot.
- Incorporated JWT authentication for meaningful user context within the chatbot.
- Integrated Apache POI to construct a Java Spring Boot micro-service to dynamically handle Excel document generation and parsing for the Direct File Import (DFI) feature.
- Leveraged GoLang and Gin to construct a micro-service to handle transferring parsed Excel DFI files to the downstream import job server.
- During quarterly close periods the DFI feature has supported 150k files globally.
- Implemented E2E file upload feature that supports files up to a maximum size of 6MB by compressing and chunking large files. This process improved the overall upload performance significantly from 40 seconds to j 5 seconds upload times with a file of 6 MB in size.

Associate Software Engineer

June 2020 - May 2021

Southbury, CT

- Utilized Artifactory and Travis CI to construct a DevOps CD pipeline to IBM Cloud k8s.
 - Constructed an E2E micro-service for handling sending user emails based on user activity.
 - Integrated ThymeLeaf for handling the creation of the emails.
 - Utilized Java Spring Boot and JDBC to construct the RESTful APIs and DB queries related to user activity emails.
 - Implemented E2E user authentication system utilizing IBM SSO and JWT.
 - Construct JWT authentication middleware into each of the Java Spring Boot and Go Gin micro-services.
 - Integrated dynamic session timeout handling for user sessions based on JWT expiration.
 - Implemented an E2E Data Table feature for the Ledger Listing page.
 - Constructed a Java Spring Boot and JDBC micro-service for handling RESTful APIs on the Ledger Listing page.
 - Utilized front-end-based pagination for enhanced data table pagination performance.
 - Created an E2E system for column filtering that utilizes the browser's local storage.
 - Leveraged Swagger in order to construct API documentation for Java, Go, and Node micro-services.

Software Engineer Intern *IBM*

May 2019 - June 2020

Southbury, CT

- Constructed a modal state management system that leverages Carbon we Design System for React.
- Leveraged Swagger in order to construct API documentation for existing micro-services.
- Implemented an E2E Data Table feature that features: front-end-based pagination, column sorting, and back-end-based column filtering.
- Participated in IBM's Hack CIO intern hackathon. Led the development of a full stack web application designed to encourage networking through matching. Integrated with Google Firebase to handle user login, account manipulation, and application data storage. Created and led the presentation of the application to a group of IBM executives and other hackathon participants.

Software Engineer Intern

June 2018 – August 2018 San Francisco, CA - Worked closely with the CTO and the engineering team to construct custom components for the Blackbird web and mobile apps leveraging React, React Native, React Native Web, GraphQL, and Apollo. Provided Quality Assurance and unit testing on multiple builds of the Blackbird web and mobile apps.

Software Engineer Intern

December 2016 - December 2016

Mack Media Group

Brookfield, CT

- Leveraged Google AMP pages to develop a mobile-first, user-friendly, and responsive home page for the agency. Worked with key stakeholders such as UI/UX designers, and the development team lead to construct the web page. This feature led to a decreased page bounce rate on mobile devices by users due to the decreased page load time that AMP boasts.

Freelance Web Designer

July 2016 - July 2016

Advanced Electrical Services Inc

New Milford, CT

- Worked closely with the client to both design and implement a revamped version of Advanced Electrical Services' website using SASS, Pug, and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science, Computer Science (Specialization: Computing Systems)

December 2023 (Expected)

Cornell College
Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science

Mt. Vernon, IA

May 2020

PROJECTS

set-me-up | https://github.com/nicholasadamou/set-me-up | Shell, Python, PHP, AppleScript October 2022 set-me-up aims to simplify the dull setup and maintenance of Mac OS development environments.

set-me-up-blueprint | https://github.com/nicholasadamou/set-me-up-blueprint | Shell A template to manage set-me-up setups.

November 2020

plex-s3fs | https://github.com/nicholasadamou/plex-s3fs | Shell

October 2019

A Plex Media Server that is backed by an Amazon S3 Bucket.

clion-gateway | https://github.com/nicholasadamou/clion-gateway | Shell, Dockerfile, CMake, C++ December 2023 A portal to CLion using JetBrains Gateway and Docker.

down-to-network | https://github.com/nicholasadamou/down-to-network | JavaScript

December 2021

Down to Network is a dynamic web / mobile app optimized to connect new fellow IBMers to experienced IBMers through the power of matching.

humblescraper | https://github.com/nicholasadamou/humblescraper | *Python*

December 2023

A small script to retrieve Name, Price/Sale, and Time information from Humble Bundle store links for use in robots or web-hooks. Uses selenium.

 $\textbf{krios-github-bot} \mid \underline{\text{https://github.com/nicholasadamou/krios-github-bot}} \mid \underline{\text{Python}}$

November 2022

A pal that keeps your dependencies up-to-date.